Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee Web Collection, 1997-2017
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
UW-Milwaukee Web Collection, 1997-2017
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee
UWM Archival Collection 221
Approximately 6 million digital files (414 GB)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Web collection of University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee websites and affiliated sites crawled by the UWM Libraries, Archives Department using the Internet Archive's Archive-It web crawler beginning in 2012, as well as pages crawled by the Internet Archive from 1997 to 2017. The web collection includes websites, blogs, Facebook pages, Flickr pages, and Twitter feeds created by various divisions, offices, and departments of the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee.
Official websites, social media accounts, and affiliated sites relating to the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. The collection was initially captured using the Internet Archive's Archive-It Web Crawler between October 2012 and January 2013, and updated periodically thereafter. The collection contains websites, Facebook pages, Twitter accounts, Flickr accounts, and other web content created by offices and divisions of the University. Most of the official pages and documents captured are hosted on the uwm.edu server, though some are housed on other subdomains and are listed separately. In addition to the UWM homepage, homepages and sub-sites for each of the University's divisions, schools, and colleges are listed separately for ease of access.
Full text search of web collection and browsing of the collection's videos are available at the collection landing page on the Archive-It site. See the entries for individual sites for additional information about the scope and content of each site.
Some entries will have links to multiple instances of their website. In most of these cases, these links indicate either that the site URL has changed dramatically, or that the Internet Archive Wayback Machine captured the page before UWM began crawling its site in 2012. The latter case is indicated as "Internet Archive Capture." Note that the Internet Archive captures typically only capture the first few levels of a given website; for more in-depth captures, please refer to the Archive-It capture.
Beginning in 2015, the UWM Archives began adding metadata points to key series on the UWM Website, including meeting minutes, Faculty Senate documents, policies and procedures, and publications landing pages. Where possible, links to such entry points are accessible through the finding aid of the parent collection. The contents list for this collection only lists the primary "seeds" or starting points for the web crawler.
The base unit of description is school, division, or office website, subdomain, or social media account. The collection is arranged into six functional series:
Main Site, 1997-2017
Academic and Research Units, 1997-2017
Administrative Units, 1997-2017
Athletics, 2000-2017
Social Media, 2009-2017
Affiliate Sites, 2012-2017
The Archive-It landing page for the collection includes more information about the materials in the collection, including site-specific and document-specific metadata and exact dates of capture.
Administrative/Restriction Information
There are no access restrictions on the materials, and the collection is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
The initial materials were collected by the UWM Archives between October 2012 and January 2013, using Internet Archive's Archive-It web capture service. Archive-It used the Heritrix web crawler to capture and archive web pages. Brad Houston ran new crawls in March and November of 2013, 2014, 2015, 2016, and in March of 2017 to add additional pages and sites to the collection.
Contents List
- 1. Main Website, 1997-2017
  - Homepage
    Homepage of the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. Most other sites in this collection are browsable from this page.
  - UWM Report: News from UW-Milwaukee
    Homepage of University Communications and Media Relations, the office responsible for external communications between UWM and the wider community. Included in the capture are press releases, feature stories, campus announcements, and back issues of campus publications created by University Communications, including the UWM Report (2006-2013); UWM Alumni, formerly UWM Today (2005-2012); UWM Research Report (2009-2012); and UWM In the News, a collection of articles from local media about UWM. As of January 2013, links to articles from the "News Archives" and "Features Archives" pages are defunct; news releases from 2011 to 2013 may be browsed through the main News page.
- 2. Academic and Research Units, 1997-2017
  - College of Engineering and Applied Science
    Established in 1964, the College of Engineering and Applied Science (CEAS) today is organized into five departments of Civil Engineering, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Industrial and Manufacturing Engineering, Materials, and Mechanical Engineering, offering both undergraduate and graduate programs in engineering and computer science. The College of Engineering and Applied Science site contains program information for prospective, incoming, and current students; student resources; listings of faculty and administrative staff; and news on featured research conducted through CEAS, including links to research centers and labs.
  - College of Health Sciences
    The College of Health Sciences is organized into seven departments of Biomedical Sciences, Communication Sciences and Disorders, Health Informatics and Administration, Kinesiology, Occupational Science and Technology, Continuing Education, and Sports and Recreation, offering both undergraduate and graduate programs, as well as certificate programs. The College of Health Sciences site provides program information and resources for future and current students; faculty and administrative staff listings and internal resources; College news; and links to research labs, clinics, and centers.
  - College of Letters and Science
    The largest of UWM's schools and colleges, the College of Letters and Sciences offers traditional liberal arts certificates, undergraduate, and graduate degrees provided throughout the 22 humanities, natural sciences, and social sciences departments of the College. The College of Letters and Sciences site provides information for prospective and current students, including material on undergraduate and graduate programs, and student services and resources; links to the College of Letters and Sciences’ academic departments; resources for faculty and staff, including departmental and administrative directories; curriculum and governance rules and reports, including assessment plans, budget reports, and faculty governance rules; minutes and agendas of the Letters and Sciences Faculty Committee; and links to the centers and institutes administered by and participating with the College of Letters and Sciences, including the Language Resource Center, Center for 21st Century Studies, and the Roberto Hernandez Center.
  - College of Nursing
    Established in 1965, the UWM College of Nursing is Wisconsin’s largest nursing school and only one of two schools that offer a full complement of degree options including Bachelor of Science, Master of Nursing, Doctor of Nursing Practice, PhD, and graduate certificates. The College of Nursing site includes information for undergraduate and graduate students, including program details, forms and materials, and student resources; faculty and staff directories; faculty research areas and actively funded research projects, with links to the College’s research centers and institutes; and resources on community and corporate partners of the College.
  - Graduate School
    The UWM Graduate School awards advanced academic degrees to graduate students who have previously earned bachelor’s degrees through undergraduate programs at UWM and elsewhere. The site includes relevant information for prospective, incoming, and current students; faculty and staff resources; academic policies and procedures; and extensive information on research conducted through the Graduate School. Minutes and agendas are also available for Graduate School committees including the Graduate Course and Curriculum Committee, the Graduate Fellowships Committee, and the Graduate Program Review Committee.
  - Helen Bader School of Social Welfare
    the Helen Bader School of Social Welfare offers undergraduate and graduate degrees to prepare students for careers in social, health, educational, and criminal justice professions. The site includes information for future and current students, including policies and procedures, and student resources; a faculty and staff directory; research resources, including links to research conducted within and in conjunction with the School; and news and events within the School.
  - Joseph J. Zilber School of Public Health
    the Zilber School of Public Health advances the understanding of health disparities, educates the local public health workforce, guides public health policy, and partners with local organizations to address community public health issues. The site includes information about the School’s certificate, master’s, and doctoral degree programs; faculty and staff listings; information on the School of Public Health Planning Council, including a listing of council members, executive summary, and full report; rosters of numerous teams and committees, including the Epidemiology PhD Work Team, School Formation Planning Committee, and the Library Resources Committee among others; and news on research initiatives, including links to the School’s laboratories.
  - Peck School of the Arts
    Home Page for the UWM Peck School of the Arts, including academic information about the school and its constitutent departments. Also included is information about admissions criteria, press releases, and a calendar of events staged by PSOA students, faculty, and guest artists.
  - Research Centers and Institutes
    As a Research I designated university, UWM encompasses a network of clinics, centers, institutes, and laboratories to accommodate the research needs of faculty, entrepreneurs, scientists, and graduate students. The UWM Centers and Institutes' site includes links for numerous centers and institutes, including the Center for Celtic Studies; the Institute on Race and Ethnicity; the Roberto Hernandez Center; and the Institute for Visual Arts (INOVA).
  - School of Architecture and Urban Planning
    Established in 1966, the School of Architecture and Urban Planning (SARUP) offers Bachelor’s, Master’s and Doctoral degrees in Architecture, a Master’s in Urban Planning, a Coordinated Master’s degree in Architecture and Urban Planning, and numerous certificate programs. The School of Architecture and Urban Planning site includes materials about the School’s programs; faculty and staff directories; galleries of student and faculty work; and news and events, including the School’s lecture series and exhibitions.
  - School of Freshwater Sciences
    Established in 2009, the School of Freshwater Sciences (SFS) is the first graduate school in the United States dedicated solely to the study of freshwater and offers research and education programs in freshwater system dynamics; human and ecosystem health; freshwater technology; and freshwater economics, policy, and management. The School of Freshwater Sciences site offers course descriptions and information on master's and doctoral degree programs; news and events; faculty and administrative staff listings; information on the School's fleet and facilities; and news on research conducted through SFS.
  - School of Information Studies
    Established in 1966, the School of Information Studies (SOIS) offers undergraduate and graduate degree programs that prepare students for careers in the information professions. The School of Information Studies site includes information for prospective and current students, including program materials, course descriptions, student resources, and links to student services; faculty and administration directories; links to SOIS social media sites; information on student and professional organizations and chapters; and notes on research conducted through the School, including faculty and student interests and funded research, workshop and funding resources, and links to the School’s research centers and groups.
  - Sheldon B. Lubar School of Business
    The AACSB accredited Lubar School of Business provides undergraduate and graduate business programs, including the nationally ranked MBA program. The Lubar School of Business site includes information for prospective, incoming, and current students; faculty and administrative staff listings; news and events; and links to the School’s research centers, including the Center for Technological Innovation, the Helen Bader Institute for Nonprofit Management, and the Bostrom Center for Entrepreneurship and Innovation among others.
  - UWM Libraries
    The UWM Libraries, formerly the UWM Golda Meir Library, accommodates the information needs of UWM faculty and students through traditional print and electronic resources and unique materials available through library departments. The site includes general information about the Libraries, including library policies, services, and staff directory; information on the Daniel M. Soref Learning Commons, including available services and policies; and links to the departments of the Libraries and the Friends of the Golda Meir Library.
- 3. Administrative Units, 1997-2017
  - Academic Affairs
    The Provost’s Office is responsible for the administration of academic affairs of the university and renders decisions on academic programming, including curricula changes; the establishment and termination of degree programs; budget decisions in the academic sector; and long-range planning for academic affairs. The site includes policies and procedures for academic program planning and review; reports and assessments of the Access to Success initiative, the campus blueprint to enhance access to UWM and increase student success; budget and planning reports and proposals; student Factbooks and entrance/exit surveys; and resources on UWM’s diversity action initiatives.
  - Alumni Association
    The UWM Alumni Association provides services for graduates of UWM and its predecessor institutions, including volunteering and networking opportunities; career counseling through Alumni Career Services; and the Alumni Association's publication, UWM Today. The site includes news on Alumni events; access to Alumni Association publications, including back issues of the UWM alumni magazine; and information on the various Alumni chapters.
  - Auxiliary Services
    The Auxiliary Services department provides support for UWM in regards to Restaurant Operations, Computer Operations, and the Center for Student Involvement. The site includes resources for UWM Panther Card and ePanther Accounts and links to departmental sites, including the UWM Bookstore; the Student Union; Neighborhood and University Housing; Restaurant Operations; Reservations and Event Planning Services; and the Student Association.
  - Campus Budget Site
    Web Resources created by the Office of the Chancellor, University Relations, and Finance and Administrative Affairs, to collect information about developments surrounding WI Act 10 (2011), WI Act 55 (2015), and the effects of the $250M cut to the UW System.
  - Finance and Administrative Affairs
    Finance and Administrative Affairs provides accounting, budgetary, personnel, IT, and other operational services for UWM. The site includes personnel and IT related policies and procedures, university weather and emergency operations procedures, and links to the individual departments of the Division of Finance and Administrative Affairs.
  - Office of the Chancellor
    The chancellor is the chief administrative officer for the university, with responsibility for overseeing UWM's administrative offices, centers, colleges, and schools. The site includes an up-to-date listing of campus leadership; communications from current Chancellor Mark Mone, including his Plenary Address and Regent Address; and links to UWM initiatives, including Access to Success, the Wisconsin Energy Resource Consortium, the Greater Milwaukee Foundation, and the Research Growth Initiative, among others.
  - Secretary of the University
    The Secretary of the University manages and facilitates governance documents at UWM, including university-wide policies and procedures and minutes/agendas of standing and ad hoc faculty and academic staff committees. Minutes and agendas for the Faculty Senate and Academic Staff Senate can be found on this site, as well as Faculty Documents, which are reports and proposals produced by committees and departments for consideration and/or approval by the Faculty Senate.
  - Student Affairs
    The Division of Student Affairs comprises of several units, which provide programs and services that support the personal and professional development of UWM students throughout their university careers. Divisional Units of the UWM Division of Student Affairs include the Career Development Center, Center for Student Involvement, the Children’s Center, the LGBT Resource Center, and Women’s Resource Center among others. The site includes general information, including campus maps, listings of campus programs and events, and Student Affairs directories; links to the Center for Student Involvement; and information regarding the Student Affairs Assessment Team.
  - University Relations
    The Division of University Relations at UWM encompasses several areas, including university communications and media relations, government relations, and neighborhood relations. The site includes links to the aforementioned divisional units; information pertaining to public records requests; and the Final Campus Master Plan report, completed in May 2010.
- 4. Athletics, 2000-2017
  - UWM Panthers
    The UWM Athletics site includes materials for all men’s and women’s sports, including current rosters, statistics, schedules and results, media guides, and news. Archived rosters, statistics, news, and media guides are available for all sports as well. The site also provides materials on the athletic department in general, including a staff directory, facilities information, a UWM Athletics Hall of Fame, and department news.
- 5. Social Media Accounts, 2009-2017
  - Facebook
    - Main UWM Account
    - Milwaukee Panthers
  - Flickr
    - Main UWM Account
  - Twitter
    - Main UWM Account
    - Milwaukee Panthers
    - UWM Alumni Association
- 6. UWM Affiliate Sites, 2012-2017
  - Media Milwaukee
    An ongoing journalism and mass media project, sponsored by the UWM Dept. of Journalism and Media Studies, focusing on local news in Milwaukee and around the UWM campus. It includes stories about events and students on campus, as well as local sports and opinions.
  - UWM Foundation
    The Mission of the UWM Foundation is to support the educational, literary and scientific endeavors of the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee by receiving, managing and distributing gifts to benefit the University's students, faculty, programs and community. Included on the site are a news feed, staffing information, and financial reports.
  - UWM Post
    Website of the UWM Post, the online-only student newspaper organization for the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. The site includes both UWM-specific original reporting and links to UWM and Milwaukee news from other news outlets around the city.